Brian Duffield

Toronto, Ontario

brianduffield@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/brianduffieldtoronto

brianduffield.github.io

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Highly experienced and versatile IT professional specializing in technical documentation with a keen focus on developer and API documentation. Experienced in the docs-as-code approach to developer documentation. Passionate about developer support including clear API docs, accurate code snippets, and working sample apps. More than 15 years of experience as a professional writer and manager, working in the Enterprise and Cloud software industry.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

API and Developer Documentation Specialist Okta Canada Sep 2020 - Current

 Deliver developer and API documentation on developer.okta.com with docs-as-code approach.

• Develop scripts, test APIs and sample apps, work on SDKs, support developers.

Manager and Documentation Specialist

Tier1 Financial Solutions Jan 2017 - Apr 2020

- Led team of 4 writers to support existing and new products built on Salesforce CRM
- Developed User Guides, OLH, and developer documentation for multiple CRM products.

Product and Documentation Specialist

Pulse Systems, Canada Feb 2016 - Oct 2018

 Developed User Guides, OLH, and Release documentation for multiple eHR products.

Documentation Manager

Oracle, Canada Mar 2006 - June 2015

 Managed multiple documentation teams within Oracle focused on developer and platform documentation.

PUBLICATIONS

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Extensive experience with technical communication industry, practices, and innovations, such as DITA, data-chunking, task-based design, minimalism, content strategy, and UX/UI integrations.

Focus on developer and API documentation, including code support, testing, and AI-assistance; experience with Postman, Redocly, VuePress, Markdown, and multiple platform and programming languages.

Over ten years of experience using Agile methodology, including writing user stories and participating in team scrums, planning, pointing, grooming, and retros.

Consistent focus on user-centered documentation: understanding the documentation audience and delivering content – in the ideal formats – to ensure client success.

Thorough understanding of web application design using HTML, HTML5, XML, CSS, and JavaScript; programming experience with PHP and other languages; database expertise with MySQL.

- Co-author of ARMA (American Record Management Association) technical report on mobile communications and security (Mobile Communications and Records and Information Management -ARMA TR-20-2012 – ISBN ISBN: 978-1-936654-08-6, published in 2012).
- LinkedIn Article: Help When You Need It.
- Published in National Post, Globe and Mail, Society of Technical Communications (STC) Intercom Magazine, and other publications.

EDUCATION

- Computer Science Certificate Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario
- Bachelor of Engineering (Civil) Carleton University, Ottawa, Ontario
- Bachelor of Science (Mathematics) Dalhousie University, Halifax, Nova Scotia